import 'package:quiz_app/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. Who wrote "War and Peace"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Leo Tolstoy',
      'b) Fyodor Dostoevsky',
      'c) Ivan Turgenev',
      'd) Alexander Pushkin',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. What is the capital of France?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) London',
      'b) Rome',
      'c) Paris',
      'd) Madrid',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. Which river is the longest in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Nile',
      'b) Amazon',
      'c) Yangtze',
      'd) Niger',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '4. Who among the following was the President of the United States of America?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Barack Obama',
      'b) George Bush',
      'c) Abraham Lincoln',
      'd) William Taft',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Which country won the first FIFA World Cup?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Argentina',
      'b) Uruguay',
      'c) Brazil',
      'd) Spain',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. Who painted the Mona Lisa?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Leonardo da Vinci',
      'b) Michelangelo',
      'c) Vincent van Gogh',
      'd) Pablo Picasso',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '7. Which famous American rock band released the album "The Wall"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) The Beatles',
      'b) Led Zeppelin',
      'c) Pink Floyd',
      'd) Nirvana',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '8. What is the title of the philosophical book written by Marcus Aurelius?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) "Little Parties"',
      'b) "The Little Prince"',
      'c) "Little Changes"',
      'd) "Meditations"',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '9. What is the highest mountain in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Mont Blanc',
      'b) Everest',
      'c) Kilimanjaro',
      'd) Mount Kilimanjaro',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '10. Which ocean is the largest by area?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Indian',
      'b) Atlantic',
      'c) Pacific',
      'd) Arctic',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '11. Which country has won the most gold medals in the Olympic Games?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) USA',
      'b) China',
      'c) Russia',
      'd) Canada',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '12.Which planet is called the "Blue Planet"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Earth',
      'b) Venus',
      'c) Neptune',
      'd) Uranus',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '13. Who was the first astronaut in the world??',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Yuri Gagarin',
      'b) Neil Armstrong',
      'c) John Glenn',
      'd) Alan Shepard',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '14. What is the highest mountain in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Colombia',
      'b) Italy',
      'c) Brazil',
      'd) India',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '15. Which of these languages has the most native speakers?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) English',
      'b) Chinese',
      'c) Spanish',
      'd) Arabic',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '16. Who wrote "Master and Margarita"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Mikhail Bulgakov',
      'b) Ivan Turgenev',
      'c) Fyodor Dostoevsky',
      'd) Anna Akhmatova',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '17. Which country is considered the birthplace of pizza?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Italy',
      'b) France',
      'c) Spain',
      'd) Greece',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '18. Which country has the largest population in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) China',
      'b) India',
      'c) USA',
      'd) Brazil',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '19. Which country is located in southwestern Europe?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Italy',
      'b) Portugal',
      'c) Spain',
      'd) Greece',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '20. Which river flows through the city of Paris?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Seine',
      'b) Thames',
      'c) Rhine',
      'd) Danube ',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '21. Who is the author of "Harry Potter"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) J.K. Rowling',
      'b) C.S. Lewis',
      'c) J.R.R. Tolkien',
      'd) J.K. Rowling ',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '22. Which river is the longest in Europe?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Volga',
      'b) Danube',
      'c) Vistula',
      'd) Dnieper',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '23. Who is the author of "A Game of Thrones"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) George R.R. Martin',
      'b) J.K. Rowling',
      'c) Stephen King',
      'd) Philip Pullman',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '24. What element on the periodic table of elements has the symbol "Fe"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Iron',
      'b) Magnesium',
      'c) Aluminum',
      'd) Potassium',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '25. Which country manufactures the most automobiles in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Germany',
      'b) Japan',
      'c) China',
      'd) USA',
    ],
  ),
];
